

UMUT KAAN ÖZDEMIR

Computer Scientist, Game Developer

y01cu.github.io

@ umutaan50@gmail.com

J +905514259473

in umut-kaan-ozdemir

9 y01cu

Ankara, Türkiye

ABOUT ME

I am a committed Computer Scientist and Game Developer with nearly three years of experience. Both my latest project, a game now available on Google Play, and my portfolio website highlight my skills and focus on creating engaging and fun digital experiences.

As a lifelong gamer, I am ready to channel my passion and technical skills into meaningful contributions. I am excited about the opportunity to collaborate with Playfinity Games' team, contributing to innovative projects and driving the future of gaming and interactive technologies together.

LANGUAGES

Turkish: Native | Birth: 2001

English: Advanced / C1

TECH STACK

Unity: VR/Mobile/PC



.NET

WebGL

GLSL

Blender

REFERENCES

Öner Önçer - Onivo Games: Owner

- in oner-oncer-413391161
- ✓ oneroncer@gmail.com

Filiz Koçoğlu - Doctoral Thesis Writer

- in filiz-koçoğlu-2349ab121

Ridvan Bal - Mayadem: Developer

- in rıdvan-bal-2b144862
- bal.rdvn@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Game Developer - Playfinity Games

= 09.2024 - still

Ankara, Türkiye

• Updating Bomballoons game.

Indie Game Developer - Onivo Games

10.2023 - 05.2024

Ankara, Türkiye (Remote)

- I have developed every aspect of our arcade idle mobile game in our two people team from scratch other than ad campaign and design.
- Link of the game -> **Gained 540** user acquisition in two weeks.

Unity Developer - Doctoral Thesis | • <-



= 09.2022 - 06.2024

Ankara, Türkiye (Remote)

- Updated ALCO-VR project for the current state of VR for a doctoral thesis. Designed and added a Turkish equivalent "meyhane" scene. Implementing the project in Meta Quest 3 right now.
- Liquid Volume, Material Editing, Level Design, Lighting

Internship - Mayadem | # <-

1 08.2022 - 09.2022

Ankara, Türkiye (Remote)

• Developed a 2D puzzle platformer game using Unity Engine. Implemented a relatively complex player controller that can climb, inventory system. Used custom animation rigging and sprite shapes.

PROJECTS

Grid Based Level Editor | • <-

• My latest project, is a runtime grid based level editor built to optimize level design and development process. It is built using specific tilemap system. Helps user place, rotate, delete objects, save, load and edit scenes with ease and speed. Fully flexible and expandable.

All of My Projects | • <-

• Including 2D, 3D games, VR projects, graduation project, Unity tools, jam games, and all other projects of mine can be found in my portfolio website. More than 20 projects are sorted considering time spent to them there.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Computer. Eng. | Gazi University, Eng. Fac.

2019 - 2023

Ankara, Türkiye